Jon White - Curriculum Vitae

7 Marsh End, Tetsworth, Thame, Oxfordshire, OX9 7AU
T: 01844 281 159 M: 07946 548 583 E: jon@bpm-web-design.co.uk W: www.bpm-web-design.co.uk

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a passionate UI Designer and Developer, with over nineteen years' experience. I'm dedicated to producing attractive, functional and standards-compliant code, whether it is for large software applications or boutique brochure websites. I have an excellent understanding of usability and design patterns that are then applied to the creation of engaging user experiences.

I keep up to date with the latest technological developments and design practices (OOCSS, Material Design etc.) and I have the interpersonal and communication skills, organisation and attention to detail necessary to develop and maintain excellent working business relationships.

SKILLS

During my professional career I have become skilled in using the following technologies, programs and software:

Primary Skills: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, Bootstrap, Responsive web design

Secondary Skills: Javascript, jQuery, AngularJS, Knockout.js, PHP, XHTML, MySQL, SEO

Production Tools: Visual Studio 2017, WAMP, Node, Yeoman, Gulp, Grunt, SourceTree, Bitbucket, Bower,

Git, SVN

Software: Photoshop, Illustrator, Fireworks, InDesign

CMS/Ecommerce: Wordpress, Joomla, OpenCart, Zen Cart, Actinic

Examples of my can be found at www.bpm-web-design.co.uk

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

March 2018 – Current: Front End Developer, Countrywide

Countrywide are the UKs largest property services group. I was involved on the website replacement project, which has undertaken to rebuild the company's 60+ brand websites using a common codebase (MVC framework) and CMS (Episerver).

The project took a modular approach to development, building component blocks (grid, form elements, tooltips, carousels etc) which could then be used within a variety of Views throughout the site. Day to day tasks including writing standard compliant HTML (Razor markup), SCSS (using BEM naming conventions) and JS (AngularJS framework) to build the component blocks. Project code management was done using Bitbucket/Git.

HTML/SCSS/CSS/AngularJS, Visual Studio 2017, Git, Bitbucket,

January 2018 – February 2018: UI Developer, BI Worldwide

I returned to BI Worldwide, working on a variety of projects within the automotive industry.

The process would be to work from design files (Photoshop) produced by the Creative department and then produce responsive, semantic HTML and SASS code. Projects were a mix of .NET and Angular, using Bootstrap 3 as the front end framework.

HTML/SASS/CSS, Bootstrap 3, Angular-UI, Visual Studio 2017

Sept 2017 - December 2017: UI Developer, Argus Media

Jon White - Curriculum Vitae

7 Marsh End, Tetsworth, Thame, Oxfordshire, OX9 7AU

T: 01844 281 159 M: 07946 548 583 E: jon@bpm-web-design.co.uk W: www.bpm-web-design.co.uk

Argus Media is a leading provider of price assessments and market data for the global energies and commodities markets. The project I was involved in was the upgrade (to Angular 4) of Argus Open Markets, a web-based commodity dealing application. This involved a switch from LESS to SASS and the incorporation of the Bootstrap 3 framework (ngx-Bootstrap and Bootstrap-SASS). I was responsible for creating the project SCSS, based upon the principles of ITCSS, ensuring a scalable and easily maintainable component-based, CSS structure.

My knowledge was also shared across the IT department so that the principles could be applied to all other current and future Argus Media projects.

HTML/SCSS/CSS/ngx-Bootstrap, Angular 4, Visual Studio 2017, Git

May 2017 – August 2017: UI Developer, BI Worldwide

BI Worldwide partner with some of the biggest UK companies and provide staff engagement solutions and services. The company is structured like a design agency; project briefs would require estimates and I worked alongside a Project Manager, Business Analyst, DB Developer and Javascript Developer to deliver first class results on projects for a variety of clients (Dell, VW, Gaggenau).

Principally the work would involve creating HTML / SASS static web pages or components, working from established style guides or Photoshop creatives. This work would then be integrated into the backend DB and support would be provided to iron out any further Front End issues. Projects were built using Angular with Angular-UI/Bootstrap markup.

HTML/SASS/CSS/Angular-UI, Visual Studio 2017

September 2016 – April 2017: UI Developer, Heath Wallace

My second spell at Heath Wallace was to provide front end development for an on-going project for the HSBC bank. The project was to build the staff user interface for loan application reviews, as the bank looked to overhaul their internal computer systems. I worked within an international team (members based in the UK, Canada and India), creating HTML/SASS code from Axshare designs. The project was built using the Angular.js framework and managed within Github.

HTML/SASS/CSS/JQuery/Angular/Node/Gulp/SourceTree/Git/

September 2015 - September 2016: UI Designer/Developer, eValue Investment Solutions

I returned to eValue for an initial six month contract (extended to one year). My main duties involved creating UI designs and rapid prototyping new financial software solutions for Nationwide, Aon and other leading financial institutes. Depending on the project I would either build prototypes based on wireframes/designs provided by the client or white label products that I developed from the conceptual stage; these would then be offered to third party clients for re-branding. Prototypes were evaluated and enhanced via user testing and client feedback within a build, measure and learn development cycle.

HTML/SASS/Bootstrap/CSS/JQuery/Knockout/NPM/Grunt/Gulp/Yeoman/Git/

June 2015 – September 2015: UI Developer, Kynetix

This was a remote-working role for a Kynetix, a company that builds software applications for the banking and exchange sector. I designed the UI for a new product, Sentinel, an ASP.Net MVC system built using a Bootstrap/Kendo UI framework. Development was done using Visual Studio 2013.

HTML/CSS/LESS/Bootstrap 3/Photoshop, Visual Studio 13

January – May 2015: UI Developer, eValue Investment Solutions

I worked on the prototyping and delivery of financial forecasting software and websites for eValue, a market-leading financial software company. Working within the UX Development team I had varied duties, primarily tasked with rebranding the 'At Retirement Planner' product for various high street

Jon White - Curriculum Vitae

7 Marsh End, Tetsworth, Thame, Oxfordshire, OX9 7AU
T: 01844 281 159 M: 07946 548 583 E: jon@bpm-web-design.co.uk W: www.bpm-web-design.co.uk

banks and financial institutes. I was also given the job of applying the Bootstrap 3 framework to an existing company promotional website which was then to be rolled out across all software products.

HTML/CSS/LESS/Bootstrap 3/Photoshop

November – December 2014: UI Developer, Jessops Europe Ltd

This was a 2 month contract role working on the Jessops and Jessops Photo websites. The main duties for this role were designing and creating website and email banner adverts plus other marketing materials. The focus was on producing high-quality work to strict deadlines.

HTML/CSS/Photoshop/Illustrator

October 2014: HTML/CSS Developer, Heath Wallace

Short term contract working for a leading Digital Media Agency, based in Reading. My role was focused on making Front End changes on two existing projects – HSBC UI prototype and a new website for the Atlantis Hotel, Dubai.

HTML/CSS/SASS

August 2013 - October 2014: UI Developer, Apprecie Ltd

This was a long-term contract role, working on a high net-worth client engagement platform. My primary roles were to create HTML/CSS template pages within a custom-built MVC framework and to develop the website UI, building a library of re-useable HTML components. There was also a lot of design work, creating mock-ups for review/approval and on-going bug fixing/site amendments. The application was built using Bootstrap 3.

HTML/LESS/CSS/Bootstrap 3/Illustrator/Photoshop/Fireworks

August 2013 – October 2013: HTML/CSS Developer, Immediate Media

I had a short contract role at a busy publishing company, working on the websites for many magazine titles such as Radio Times and Gardeners World. Fundamentally the work involved taking a design and converting it into HTML/CSS for responsive Newsletter and Promotional emails, website Advertorials and online competitions.

HTML/CSS/Photoshop/Fireworks

QUALIFICATIONS & EDUCATION

BSc Media Technology: Leeds Metropolitan University, 1996 – 2000

3 A Levels and 8 GCSEs: Sir William Borlase Grammar School, Marlow, 1986 - 1990

PERSONAL DETAILS

Interests: Musician – Guitar & Drums, home recording. I was in the band Blind Mr. Jones (2000 – 2006) with whom I released two albums via Cherry Red Records. I'm also a keen reader and interested in (although no longer playing!) all sorts of sport. I swim and jog regularly for fitness.

REFERENCES

Available on request.